New research suggests that pandas may be at risk of dying out because they are too comfortable.
新研究表明，大熊猫可能因为过得太舒适而面临灭绝的危险。
Experts say too much happiness can stop the bears from searching for new mates.
专家称，太过快乐可能会让大熊猫不去寻找新的配偶。
Environmentalists have long believed that building roads or homes near the bears may threaten their survival by “reducing or fragmenting their natural habitats”, The Times reported.
据《泰晤士报》报道，环保人士长期以来一直认为，在大熊猫附近修路或建房可能会“使它们的自然栖息地缩小或破碎化”，从而威胁其生存。
But the new research suggests that a “modest degree of discomfort and fragmentation” may actually help preserve panda populations.
但这项新研究表明，“程度适中的不适和破碎化”实际上可能有助于保护大熊猫种群。
The research was conducted by scientists from Michigan State University.
这项研究是由密歇根州立大学的科学家开展的。
It concluded that pandas fail to wander off in search of new mates if they find their habitat too comfortable, resulting in a lack of vital genetic diversity.
研究得出结论：如果大熊猫觉得自己的栖息地太舒适，就不会离开原地四处游荡、寻找新的配偶，从而导致缺乏至关重要的遗传多样性。
For their study—outlined in a paper in the journal Conservation Biology—the team looked at genetic diversity and spread among a Chinese panda population.
这项研究的概要见于《保护生物学》期刊上的一篇论文。在研究中，该团队考察了中国一个大熊猫种群的遗传多样性和扩散情况。
The ideal level of perfectly livable habitat was found to be only 80% of an area, with the remainder either too harsh or too affected by human activity.
研究发现，在一片区域中，完全宜居的栖息地理想占比仅为80%，其余部分要么环境太恶劣，要么受人类活动影响太大。
The experts concluded that pandas should ideally “be happy enough to thrive, but not so content that they don’t want to move around and find new mates”.
专家们得出结论：理想情况下，大熊猫应该“足够快乐，能茁壮成长，但又不至于满足到不想四处走动、寻找新的配偶”。
Their conclusions about what The Guardian described as this “sweet spot” are in line with the so-called Goldilocks principle: that there can be just the right amount of something.
对于《卫报》所称的这一“最佳点”，他们得出的结论与所谓的“金发姑娘原则”相符，即事物可以有一个恰到好处的量。
The concept has been applied to a wide range of disciplines, from developmental psychology to economics and engineering.
这一概念已广泛应用于各个学科领域，从发展心理学到经济学，再到工程学。
Claudio Sillero, a professor of conservation biology at Oxford University, told the newspaper that the new findings could have implications beyond panda conservation.
牛津大学保护生物学教授克劳迪奥·西列罗对该报表示，这些新发现的意义可能不止于大熊猫保护。
“Most large animals that eat meat live in increasingly fragmented landscapes,” said Sillero, who was not involved in the research.
并未参与这项研究的西列罗说：“大多数大型食肉动物都生活在日益破碎化的景观中。”
“It may well be that the messy nature of their relationship with human endeavour induces more animals to scatter or travel further, and might result in greater genetic connectivity and enhanced population persistence.”
“很可能，它们与人类活动之间纷乱的关系促使更多动物分散开来或走得更远，并可能带来更强的遗传连通性，增强种群的存续能力。”
The most recent count of pandas found that there were more than 1,800 left in the wild, putting them on the list of vulnerable, but not endangered, species.
最近一次大熊猫数量统计发现，野外现存1800多只大熊猫，它们因此被列入易危物种名单，而非濒危物种名单。